that's when things start to line up yeah
and the more you're in that space the
more they line up and so the question is
if you're like really in that space
how much do things line up I've had
experiences where everything came
together you know and and and there are
very very powerful experiences and and
they're they're also characterized by
it's like everything turns into a
musical symphony where each part is
exactly appropriate for that moment and
and I think music actually expresses
that which is partly why music produces
transcendent experiences you know I
think it is an intimation of Paradise
it's something like that and you can
think about that psychologically you
know because it also makes sense
psychologically that your optimal
experiences are going to occur when
you're most United with yourself and but
I don't know what see we don't exactly
understand the relationship between our
consciousness and the world we're at our
best when we're integrated completely
and there is an effect of that
integration in principle on what we
would normally regard as external
reality because external reality can
line up with that integration as well
and so-called external reality you know
I also think that figures like the
Buddha you know he's an exemplar of the
possibilities of that alignment and the
exercise is the yogic exercises for
example our attempts to bring that
alignment into being you know I mean
it's very centred on the body which is
quite interesting even though it's a
spiritual tradition right it's very very
centered on the body and I think people
probably experience that when they have
peak sexual experiences with someone you
know where there's real intimacy because
they're in the same place at the same
time and everything comes together for
that moment you know maybe literally yes
yes literally right and and and I also
don't think that that linguistic usage
is chance right because I think that's a
place where that experience is
a brief intimation of of heaven that
might be a way of thinking about it